# Saad M. Rassam

Greater Charlotte, NC Area

## SMRassam@gmail.com | (585)474-3726

LinkedIn: <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/saadrassam/">https://www.linkedin.com/in/saadrassam/</a> | GitHub: <a href="https://github.com/Srassam/responsive\_porfolio">https://github.com/Srassam/responsive\_porfolio</a>

#### **Summary**

Experienced Software Engineer in object-oriented programming and problem solving. Developed multiple applications based on market need. Quick learner of new technologies; successful working in both team and self-directed settings. Certified Scrum Master who has led multiple teams from daily standups to retrospectives.

#### **Technical Skills**

Languages: CSS, HTML, JavaScript Databases:MySQL, MongoDB Tools: Git and Heroku

## **Projects**

#### **OSGEO**

Github: https://github.com/Srassam/OSGEO
Deployed: https://srassam.github.io/OSGEO/.

- Created app to determine what operating system user is on and where they are located.
- The code is mostly JavaScript with a starter html file.

#### **Pomodoro Timer**

Github: https://github.com/Srassam/PomodoroTimer

Deployed: <a href="https://srassam.github.io/PomodoroTimer/">https://srassam.github.io/PomodoroTimer/</a>

- Created an app for users to keep track of time for studying and breaks.
- The app uses html,css, and JavaScript.
- Time is stored in local storage, if the user decides to pause and not start over.

### Restaurant Finder

Github:https://github.com/Srassam/Project\_1\_Restaurant\_Finder Deployed: https://srassam.github.io/Project\_1\_Restaurant\_Finder/

- Created an app using web API to find restaurants in proximity of the users location.
- The user is prompted to pick from a number of restaurant categories and radius.
- App generates top 3 restaurants, with options of expanding the results .
- Software used HTML Bootstrap, CSS and Javascript.

## **Experience**

## **UNCC Full Stack Bootcamp**

07/2020-11/2020

Successfully achieved certificate in Full Stack Development. Created multiple applications using the three languages of the web, set up servers, captured and stored data by building multiple databases.

## Allstate Ivantage

# **Property and Casualty Producer**

04/2018-07/2020

Utilized multiple selling platforms to quote, underwrite, and close new business. Coached team members on best practices of daily operations, selling and goal setting. Partnered with agents, carriers and technology programs to deliver an efficient sales and service model.

# Paychex

## Property and Casualty Representative

09/2017-02/2018

Drove the sales of commercial insurance products including workers compensation, business owners' policies, commercial automotive, and general liability for small and midmarket clients. Generated quotes through multiple carriers to deliver competitive rates. Regularly met or exceeded goals by managing an active pipeline.

#### Education

# University of North Carolina at North Charlotte 07/2020-10/2020

Certificate

Completed Full Stack Web Development bootcamp program. Main focus on back end development, setting up databases and servers.

#### University of Florida Gainesville, FL 06/2005-06/2008

Bachelor of Science, Anthropology

Studied social, political, economic, and environmental systems within cultures.